<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Ingots of learning</title>
    <link>https://drdjing.github.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Ingots of learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://drdjing.github.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it a wasp or a bee?</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/beeorwasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/beeorwasp/</guid>
      <description>Rcently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning fastai methodology to create image recognition nets, with the ultimate goal of determining cloud types, and bee genus&amp;rsquo;. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on it for a bit, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to show some of my progress, and I&amp;rsquo;ll start with my Bee classification net.
This post is about my bee net. Initially, the idea was to classify bees according to their genus, and this is still on the books for later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning practical machine learning</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/mllearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/mllearning/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled a bit in machine learning (ML) before, having taking the introductory course by the famous Andrew Ng on Coursera (LINK). However, upon digging a bit deeper, MATLAB is somewhat outdated to use as a basis for ML tasks these days. Additionally, while the course provided a solid foundation for understanding different types of ML learning algorithms, from a more practical point of view it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as useful. Mostly because the majority of the assignments were mostly pre-filled, leaving the student to create one or two functions that were essentially copy-pasting a piece of math from the lecture slides into MATLAB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labjack take 3</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack3/</guid>
      <description>So the new U3&amp;rsquo;s came in, and they are very sleek. I also ordered some of the LJ-Tick addons, which take a couple of open FIO (flexible I/O) ports and &amp;ldquo;converts&amp;rdquo; them to DAC&amp;rsquo;s (digital analog control [I think]) with +/- 10 V capabilities.
So this delivery of hardware should solve the two big problems that I was having when using a single U6 - namely that the DAC&amp;rsquo;s on any of the U-series Labjacks only support a USB voltage of0-4 V (at least to my knowledge), and a serious timing issue I was having while attempting to stream data whilst simultaneously sending read/write commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reworking the LabJack interface</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack2/</guid>
      <description>This blog post was originally going to be about how great I am at making programs, and how my program was practically finished, etc. Unfortunately, however, real life has a way of bringing you back to reality, often in less than ideal ways.
This time, it brought me back with the realisation that because of USB limitations, I cannot multi-thread data from a streaming Labjack and simultaneously command/response a signal output with enough fine time control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labjack experiments</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/labjack/</guid>
      <description>My current job has me do a lot of random bits and pieces, very little coherent &amp;ldquo;This is your job&amp;rdquo; tasks. To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a website [LINK], studied Machine Learning, decided it was overkill for the image recognition program I then created, and helped to write a paper or two. Now, however, I am stepping well outside of my comfort area and attempting to modernize the interface between a computer and a two-decade old piece of lab equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>