<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Ingots of learning</title>
    <link>https://drdjing.github.io/categories/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Ingots of learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://drdjing.github.io/categories/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Idle clicker game</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gameidleclick1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gameidleclick1/</guid>
      <description>For my first full game, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do an idle clicker. You know, like Cookie Clicker but with a different theme. Given 2020, and my unemployment, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to make it a job-search themed clicker.
The basic idea is that every click is a job application. As more and more applications are sent out, the rejections start rolling in. Motivation builds as your progress, which lets you buy &amp;ldquo;auto-clickers&amp;rdquo; which will automatically apply for jobs for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First simple game</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gamedevtut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gamedevtut/</guid>
      <description>Following the tutorial given in the Godot documentation was a simple and easy task. They provide all the assets, code snippets, etc, to get you up and running with a simple avoidance game.
The game itself is relatively straight forward, but the tutorial teaches you many valuable things about the way Godot works, including an introduciton to its Node system (very cool, btw), how to instantiate scenes, emission and receival of signals, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting in Game Development</title>
      <link>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gamedevstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drdjing.github.io/blog/gamedevstart/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a man of many ideas. Wanting to develop a simple game, then move onto more complex ones, is one of those ideas. Of course, many have done this before me and many will after me, so I have no qualms about standing on the shoulders of giants, and using a game engine that suits my needs.
Now, onto that. In the game engine world, there are two contenders that everyone knows about (so far as I can tell).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>